<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Antique Music Video on Luke Jaeger</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/tags/antique-music-video/</link><description>Recent content in Antique Music Video on Luke Jaeger</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trickfilm.github.io/tags/antique-music-video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Take Off Your Skin</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/take-off-your-skin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/take-off-your-skin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After spending a week in the hospital with a severe viral infection that caused most of my skin to fall off, I found myself humming this 1929 pop song that my mom used to sing. This film is dedicated to her memory. A light dusting of climate anxiety and body horror complement the mood. The medical image appearing on the monitor in the MRI room is the spinal column of one of my early animation studio bosses / mentors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>When Me Body Lay Down In The Grave</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/when-me-body-lay-down-in-the-grave/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/when-me-body-lay-down-in-the-grave/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The third in a series of “antique music videos” is a requiem for the numberless laborers who died building our physical and cultural environment. A haunting, minor-key shout recorded in 1938 accompanies the imagery of hard labor and death in the subterranean spaces and skyscraper steelwork of New York.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rabbit Tracks</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/rabbit-tracks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/rabbit-tracks/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A journey through a mortality-infused landscape populated by mysterious chickens, inconvenient frogs, and other cartoonish creatures.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carolina Shout</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/carolina-shout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/carolina-shout/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another in a series of “antique music videos,” set to a 1921 composition by jazz pioneer &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_P._Johnson"&gt;James P. Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, an originator of the Harlem Stride piano style. The animation reflects the multi-leveled, over-the-top delight and frantic silliness of this amazing musical performance.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In bringing these old musical treasures to new audiences I hope to recreate in some small way the experience of hearing this music for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Old Joe's Hittin The Jug</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/old-joes-hittin-the-jug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/old-joes-hittin-the-jug/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Music by 1930s hot jazz fiddler Stuff Smith accompanies a mix of live action, stop-motion and puppetry, including a 15-foot-high plywood marionette suspended from a highway overpass (and no we didn&amp;rsquo;t ask permission). Shot entirely outdoors in various weed-choked, industrial-looking locations in Northampton, Massachusetts, the film draws a parallel between these neglected, formerly useful sites which have gone to seed, and the musical treasures which the ever-changing machineries of cultural production have left in obscurity. Shot on 16mm film during the hottest week of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Out The Fire</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/out-the-fire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/out-the-fire/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;An antique music video homage to the animation of the Fleischer Studios, set to a 1946 calypso about the New York City Fire Department. The film functions as a fun cartoon but also mourns the disappeared past of New York and asserts the power of music as a mechanism for retrieving the unretrievable. Cel and paper animation, shot on 16mm film.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Major W.E. Power (Inspector Constabulary) was also an officer in the Trinidad Fire Brigade. William O&amp;rsquo;Dwyer served as Mayor of New York City from 1946 to 1950.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>