<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music Video on Luke Jaeger</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/tags/music-video/</link><description>Recent content in Music Video on Luke Jaeger</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trickfilm.github.io/tags/music-video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gather Up (Grant-Lee Phillips)</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/gather-up/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/gather-up/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Music Video for Grant-Lee Philips “Gather Up.” \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the album “Lightning, Show Us Your Stuff,” on &lt;a href="https://www.yeproc.com/"&gt;Yep Roc Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The song&amp;rsquo;s lyrics and mood suggest the preachings of an old-time sidewalk prophet warning of imminent disaster. With this atmosphere as guide, I composited footage of Grant (it was important that he be barefoot) into a series of foreboding hand-painted environments. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly pleased with the color palette, especially the greens and yellows.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
With every project I try to learn at least one new technique or process. Here I pushed myself to develop some custom particle effects (steam, fog, and windblown leaves). I also assigned randomized parameters to some elements (like the trees losing their leaves and the birds converging on the ark-spaceship) for more naturalistic choreography.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Love's In Need Of Love Today | a multitrack extravaganza</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/loves-in-need-of-love-today-a-multitrack-extravaganza/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/loves-in-need-of-love-today-a-multitrack-extravaganza/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In May of 2020, at the height of the COVID-19 pandemic, 60 Pioneer Valley musicians came together to record a Stevie Wonder song of hope in an effort to bring attention to the plight of their fellow artists and a relief fund started by the Northampton Arts Council. We raised a bunch of money and had some indoor fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Holding Onto Light</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/holding-onto-light/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/holding-onto-light/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Music video for Philip Price &amp;ldquo;Holding Onto Light&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Another grab-bag of composited imagery: paper and ProCreate animation by me and Philip, repurposed album artwork by &lt;a href="https://trevstair.myportfolio.com/work"&gt;Trev Stair&lt;/a&gt;, 19th century police mugshots, other natural flavors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Take Off Your Skin</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/take-off-your-skin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/take-off-your-skin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After spending a week in the hospital with a severe viral infection that caused most of my skin to fall off, I found myself humming this 1929 pop song that my mom used to sing. This film is dedicated to her memory. A light dusting of climate anxiety and body horror complement the mood. The medical image appearing on the monitor in the MRI room is the spinal column of one of my early animation studio bosses / mentors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rabbit Tracks</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/rabbit-tracks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/rabbit-tracks/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A journey through a mortality-infused landscape populated by mysterious chickens, inconvenient frogs, and other cartoonish creatures.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Celia Johnson (Winterpills)</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/celia-johnson-winterpills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/celia-johnson-winterpills/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Public domain and original imagery combine in this lush &lt;a href="https://www.signaturesounds.com/artists#/winterpills/"&gt;Winterpills&lt;/a&gt; music video, bursting with an abundance of exotic plants, extinct fauna, and antique illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dying Star (Winterpills)</title><link>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/dying-star-winterpills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trickfilm.github.io/art/dying-star-winterpills/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A subterranean landscape of found and archival footage forms a lush backdrop for this sad and enigmatic song by &lt;a href="https://www.signaturesounds.com/artists#/winterpills/"&gt;Winterpills&lt;/a&gt;. From the album &lt;a href="https://winterpillsmusic.bandcamp.com/album/all-my-lovely-goners"&gt;&amp;ldquo;All My Lovely Goners&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; on Signature Sounds / Soft Alarm.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I started out by searching YouTube for footage of freight trains. What I found was &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JAPibSxgIyw"&gt;Elizabeth Cotton singing &amp;ldquo;Freight Train&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; in 1957 on Pete Seeger&amp;rsquo;s TV show. (Who knew Pete Seeger had a TV show?)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Then the algorithm threw the James Baldwin footage at me, and I decided to submit to the logic of the search engine, gathering imagery using a sort of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flarf_poetry"&gt;Flarf poetry&lt;/a&gt; approach. When I saw how Allen Ginsberg&amp;rsquo;s finger-gesture lined up with the piano riff, I had to go with it.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I threw all this footage in the blender along with some handmade artwork and a bunch of Hi-8 footage I&amp;rsquo;d shot in the NYC subway in the 1990&amp;rsquo;s. The dreamlike final shot, a view out the front window of a train barreling down tracks overgrown with weeds and trees, was (and is) incredibly mysterious and compelling to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>